Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/thi-nguyen-a0320b21b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

New Business Development Strategic Business Development Build Strong Relationships

Thi Nguyen

Project Manager | E-commerce | Marketing | Commercial Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Summary

More than 5 years of experience in e-commerce. With a sense of responsibility, an enthusiastic personality, and a spirit of learning, I always make sure to complete the assigned work. Learning and growing myself, I want to secure a promising position where I have the opportunity to improve my skills and growth and share the knowledge and experiences I have

Experience

IME Global Agency Project Manager April 2024 - Present (1 year) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Ecommerce & Affiliate Planning:

- Develop strategies and makes in-depth recommendations based on a strong grasp of analytics, eCommerce Affiliate marketing & Influencers Affiliate
 Campaign
- Manages the daily workflow of all client campaigns, and works with various internal and external stakeholders, including Ecommerce Retailers (Shopee, Tiki, Lazada), Social Commerce Channel (TikTok) and Affiliate Publishers to deliver campaign objectives.
- Supervise and plan e-commerce plan (promotions, exclusive deals, special offers, ...) & Affiliate incentive plan
- Managed and assigned tasks to marketing and operations staff, designers, and customer service to ensure effective work.
- Work closely with the KOLs/KOCs team on commercial/incentive planning, and operation
- Analyze data and structure relevant information for the client's benefit Performance and Optimization:
- Timely execution of promotional levers to deliver against strategic category goals

- Optimize promotional effectiveness on eCommerce Campaigns, specific Affiliate Programs, and well collaboration with KOL/KOCs to win D-day and achieve P&L monthly
- In charge of campaign implementation, and budget management on relevant eCommerce platforms (Tiki, Shopee, Lazada....), other online acquisition channels: affiliate marketing, social commerce media to achieve GMV target.
- Work closely with E-Retail partners & Affiliate Vendors
- Forecast sales performance trends (GMV, ROAS), provide solutions on optimization and quick actions to meet the KPIs within a very tight period
- Responsible for regular reports on Ecommerce campaigns (daily, monthly, campaign)
- Monitor competition and provide suggestions for improvement

AceCom Technologies Ecommerce Brand Leader 2023 - April 2024 (1 year)

Vietnam

- Developed business plans for e-commerce stores, including sales strategy, marketing plan, pricing, promotions, campaigns, and budget allocation.
- Established and maintained relationships with brands, agencies, and e-commerce platforms (Lazada, Shopee, Tiki, TikTok).
- Managed and assigned tasks to marketing and operations staff, designers, and customer service to ensure effective work.
- Planned and managed the annual e-commerce campaign calendar based on brand and partner activities.
- Monitored e-commerce trends, initiatives, and market best practices.
- Ensured consistent SEO-optimized content and images for SKUs to enhance customer experience and increase conversion rates.
- Strategically allocated budgets for marketing activities, including internal advertising and affiliate advertising, and executed media plans for Mega Sale campaigns.
- Analyzed sales data and provided insights.

Evaluated campaigns and suggested new sales strategies.

Researched and evaluated competitors' online sales programs to develop business strategies for boosting e-commerce sales.

- Collaborated closely with brands to clarify project requirements.
- Reported on campaign effectiveness during and after each campaign.

rang rang coffee Ecommerce Leader

2022 - November 2022 (less than a year)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Planned and executed e-commerce campaigns, developing new marketing tactics and promotional activities on platforms such as Shopee, Lazada, Tiki, and delivery apps, as well as the company's website to boost awareness, traffic, and conversions.
- Managed and assigned tasks to marketing and operations staff to ensure effective workflow.
- Conducted market surveys and research, analyzing information to identify development opportunities and strategies for product lines.
- Effectively managed and coordinated all forms of advertising across channels.
- Identified each platform's role, set targeting, budget allocation, and KPIs to achieve campaign objectives.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams for media bookings on Facebook, Google, TikTok, YouTube, CRM, website solutions, landing pages, and online store launches to optimize media channels as planned.
- Ensured seamless collaboration among internal product and operation teams during campaigns to meet company goals.
- Reported weekly and monthly results to the Head of Department and shared learnings for future planning

Jet Commerce

2 years 11 months

Ecommerce Marketing Planner
July 2020 - July 2021 (1 year 1 month)

Vietnam

- Managed and controlled product and brand appearance in SIS, ensuring the store is always presented in a good manner and best practices for shopper experience.
- Planned and managed a full-year e-commerce campaign calendar based on brand and partner activities, especially during peak e-commerce seasons: Super Brand Day, Platform birthday, 9.9, 11.11, 12.12, Tet.

Worked closely with partner brands to develop key visual ideas, design styles, and colors for campaigns.

- Conceptualized and developed interesting and relevant campaigns to execute specific strategic directions such as new product launches and cobranding.
- Collaborated with internal stakeholders (Commercial, Digital, E-Merchandising, Creative, Finance, OPS) and external partners to deliver best-

in-class e-commerce campaigns, consumer experience, and business results/ KPIs from planning to execution.

- Planned and tracked media planning for all channels and executed Mega Sale campaigns to generate traffic and achieve GMV KPIs (Paid Search, CPAS, Affiliate, Platform Display Ads).
- Liaised with related teams (Commercial, Data, CS) to provide campaign performance insights and evaluations, suggesting key learnings to share with brands and partners.
- Identified each platform's role, set targeting, budget allocation, and KPIs across platforms to carry out campaign objectives.
- Analyzed data to help define which SKUs to focus on for well-planned campaigns.
- Conducted market surveys and research, analyzing information to identify development opportunities and strategies for product lines.
- Reported monthly results to the manager and shared learnings for future planning.

Commercial Design Supervisor September 2018 - September 2020 (2 years 1 month) Vietnam

Stars Media VN
Graphic Designer
March 2018 - August 2018 (6 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

MIOTO Marketing and Design 2017 - 2018 (1 year) Vietnam

Education

University of Finance & Marketing - UFM
Bachelor of Business Administration, Business Administration, Management and Operations · (2013 - 2017)